It's really coming down now. The forecast was off, eh?
好大的雨，天氣預報不準了啊，日鶴
Forecast, prediction, warning, expectation, plan, prophecy.
預報、預測、預告 預判、預定、預知
Things that tell of the future have never been reliable.
自古以來有「預」字的從來都靠不住
Are you sure it's under here?
真的在這下面嗎？
Yes. I have a bad feeling.
對，因為我有種不好的預感
Let's hope my feeling is off too.
希望是我的預感出錯吧
Run!
快跑
Don't stop!
別停下來
Damn.
可惡
They haven't attacked me at all.
從一開始就完全沒來攻擊我
Ushioh!
潮
Does your arm hurt?
你的手臂痛嗎？
Oh no, we can't go any further.
不行，無法繼續前進了
Get out of here! Go!
別擋路，讓開
Sou!
窗
Awesome! Is this why you brought the insecticide?
漂亮，你就是為了這個目的 才帶殺蟲劑的嗎
Yeah! Just like I thought.
對，和我想的一樣
They're afraid of fire. You okay, Ushioh? We can still go back.
沒有不怕火的生物，你沒事吧？潮 現在還能折返
I'm fine!
我沒事
Let's keep going. I hate leaving things halfway!
我們要走到底，我最討厭半途而廢了
Figured you'd say that.
我想也是
Shinpei! I'll open a path. Take care of Ushioh.
慎平，我負責開路，潮就拜託你了
You got it!
這還用說嗎？
Ryunosuke! Tell me when you're gonna shoot!
喂，龍之介，要開槍就說一聲啊 耳朵都要被震聾了
Sorry, but you'd be dead if I waited at all.
抱歉，可是說完再開槍我們會死的
Can't believe these shadows are lurking underneath the island.
不過真沒想到這島的地下 潛伏著這麼多影子，怎麼會這樣？
There are more of them. Their nest is close.
數量增加了，那些傢伙的巢穴 就在這附近
The number you have called is out of the range of…
你所打的電話不在服務區或已關機…
Where is Shinpei? He went out to see Sou.
小慎去哪裡了？說去見窗就出門了
I can't reach Sou or Tokiko either.
窗的電話也打不通，朱鷺子也不接
Shinpei. Come home soon.
小慎，快點回來吧
Shadow sickness already took Sis and Shiori. Not Shinpei too!
因為影子病，姐姐死了 詩織也消失了，要是連小慎都出事…
Isn't this Shiori's hair tie?
這是詩織的髮圈？
Over here.
這邊
Shinpei is here…
慎平哥哥在這邊…
What? Wait!
甚麼？等一下
Watch out… M-Mio?
危險，小澪？
Oh, Tetsu. Sorry.
哲哥，抱歉
Don't jump out like that. What's going on? You look pale.
別這樣突然衝出來啊 你怎麼了？臉色都變了
It's Shiori! Didn't you see her?
我剛才看到詩織了，你沒看到嗎？
What? Was she found? Where is she?
甚麼？找到她了嗎？在哪裡？
She went running the way you came from.
剛才往哲哥來的方向跑了
No way, I only saw you running.
你在說甚麼？我只看到你跑過來了
Shiori!
詩織
What?
甚麼？
She disappeared.
消失了？
Hey wait…
喂，等等
The manhole lid is loose.
這個下水道口的蓋子移開了
Shinpei is here…
慎平哥哥在這邊
What does that mean? Is Shinpei down there?
怎麼回事？是說小慎在這裡面？
There's no way a little girl would go inside this thing!
一個小學女生怎麼可能鑽進這裡面？
Normally, I'd agree.
照理來說的確…
But what if it was Shiori's shadow?
可是如果剛才那個是詩織的影子呢？
-Tetsu… -Hell, no.
-哲哥 -我不要
I didn't even say anything!
我甚麼都還沒說
You want me to check inside, right? No way! I'm a busy man!
你是要我下去調查吧，不行 我沒時間，我可是很忙的
I'm on my way to the city for drinks!
我現在要去都酒吧喝酒
If I show up smelling like the sewers, Erika will hate me for sure!
要是身上沾到臭味還是髒東西 繪里香會嫌棄的
So drinks are worth more than a human life to you?
喝酒比人命重要嗎？
-You'd be a hero. -What?
這是立功的機會
A hero who finds a missing girl would be all over the news.
英雄警官找到了下落不明的女孩 這種新聞上了報紙…
You'd be famous. Erika would totally fall for you.
你就能一躍成為名人了 繪里香也會對你刮目相看吧
But I won't force you. I'm going with or without you.
不過你不想去就算了，攔著我也沒用 我就算一個人也會去
Follow me.
跟我來吧
It's not like I wanna be a hero and get girls, don't get me wrong!
不，我可不是為了立功和受歡迎 別誤會我啊
I'm an ally of justice who just wants to find Shiori!
我只是身為正義的夥伴 想要找到詩織而已
Being superficial is totally better than doing nothing.
你選擇了採取行動的偽善 而不是甚麼都不做的善
Isn't that a little harsh, Mio?
你是不是話裡帶刺？小澪
Did we escape them?
總算甩掉了
Yeah… but what is this place?
是啊，但這是甚麼地方？
It's starting to look even stranger.
這裡的景色也很奇怪
Yeah, look. This is impossible.
是啊，你們看，這太不可思議了
What?
甚麼？
These are corals. How can sea animals live on land?
這是珊瑚吧 為甚麼地上會長出海裡的生物？
They're shadows.
是影子
What?
甚麼？
The corals, sea anemones, and barnacles are all shadows.
這些珊瑚、海葵，還有藤壺 全都是影子
Who would do anything like this?
到底是誰做的？
I don't know, but someone printed the sea here.
不清楚，但應該是有人 在這裡列印出了海
It's seawater. This must be connected to the sea.
是海水，這裡果然是與大海相連的
It'd be great if we can find another way to get out.
要是還有其他出口的話 那倒是個好消息
This is getting too dangerous, Shinpei.
再往裡面走就危險了，慎平
I've used up all the gas too. It's over if we get attacked again.
殺蟲劑的氣也都用完了 要是再遭到襲擊，我們就完了
I'm okay. Just hungry.
我沒事，只是肚子餓了
How is that possible? We just ate an hour ago!
這也太奇怪了 我們才剛吃過，還不到一個小時
That's not your usual hunger.
你應該不是單純的肚子餓吧
Your right arm hasn't healed, has it?
你的右手臂並沒有痊癒，對吧
This is damaged data from my real body.
這是本體受的傷，也就是資料損壞
To heal it, I need food.
治療需要進食才行
Then Shinpei can give you another rice ball…
那讓慎平再捏幾個飯糰…
No. I don't mean normal food.
不行，不是普通的進食
The only way to repair this data is to rescan the original.
只有再對原型掃描一次 才能恢復資料
But Ushio was cremated. I can't repair this wound.
但潮已經變成灰燼 所以我的傷無法治好了
A-Are you serious?
不是吧
All this time, it's been hurting since the shadow Mio stabbed you yesterday?
你一直在忍耐嗎？ 從昨天被影子澪襲擊一直到現在？
I wasn't sure until just now.
我是剛剛才確定的
Why did you keep something so important from us?
這麼重要的事情為甚麼不說？
Sorry. I'll erase my right arm for now. That will take away the pain.
抱歉，總之我先讓右臂消失吧 這樣痛感也會隨之消失了
No way to heal it? That can't be.
沒有治療的方法，怎麼會這樣？
She is getting weaker, dammit. I can't let her die again.
她越來越虛弱了，可惡 我絕不能讓她再死一次
What if I loop, or turn back the time? How would that heal it?
輪迴就可以了嗎？時間倒流 就能治好傷吧，可是該怎麼做？
Don't move.
別動
Turn around slowly.
慢慢轉過身來
If you two make any sudden moves, it will cost you Ushioh's life.
你們兩個要是有甚麼可疑的舉動 潮姐姐可就沒命了
W-What are you doing here?
你怎麼會在這裡？
Tokiko!
朱鷺子
It's a dead end.
是死路
Shadows came from here. It's a path only they can go through.
影子們就是從這邊來的 這是那些傢伙的專用通道嗎？
We know one thing now.
這下就很清楚了
Shadows used these sewers and tunnels to move around the island.
影子們是通過下水道等地下通道 在島上移動的
Yeah. The army dug a lot of these in this area.
嗯，而且這一帶的地下 被軍隊挖過好幾遍，亂七八糟的
No one even knows the entire layout anymore.
沒有人知道它的全貌是怎麼樣的
There could be many of these passages.
這樣的通道有多少條都不奇怪
What should we do? We don't have tools to cut steel bars.
可是該怎麼辦呢？ 我們也沒有能切斷鐵柵欄的工具
Should we go back up and find another way in?
要先上去找找其他入口嗎？
Based on the map, we're near the center of the island.
從地圖上來看 這裡似乎正好是島的正中央
No. There probably isn't an entrance that humans can use.
不用，恐怕是沒有出入口 至少沒有人類能通過的出入口
Take a look ahead. This isn't a sewer.
你看，這前面和下水道不同
It's a natural cave that was always here.
這是本來就存在的天然洞窟
Hiruko's grotto really existed.
莫非蛭子洞真的存在嗎？
My gramps told me about it when I was a kid.
小時候我聽爺爺說過
There's a massive underground cave in Hitogashima Island.
日都島的地下橫亙著一個巨大的洞穴
That's Hiruko's grotto.
那就是蛭子洞
Until the mid-Meiji era, an entrance appeared during the low tide…
明治中期時，在港口的附近 有一個只有退潮時才會出現的出入口
but the army closed it up during the First Sino-Japanese War.
甲午戰爭期間，軍隊在整頓港口時 把那個出入口塞住了
Hiruko's grotto is an island legend that I thought was a myth.
這個島上的傳說，我還以為是老作的
It's where our guardian god Hiruko lived…
據說很久以前 那裡就是日都島的守護神蛭子大人
after drifting to Hitogashima Island.
漂流到這座島上後所居住的地方
That's Hiruko's Lore. Sis would know more. Should we switch?
蛭子傳說，對吧？ 姐姐應該很清楚，要換她來嗎？
Not right now.
暫時不要
We can ask the Karikiri boy, but I wish his old man was alive.
問雁切家那小子也行 如果他父親還活著的話
The man might have known something. Anyways, let's go back and get tools…
他也許知道些甚麼，不管怎麼樣 我們還是需要鋸子，先回去…
Quiet.
噓，先別說話
Hey, let's just go back. She won't be in here.
行了嗎？不如回去吧 不可能會在這種地方
It was Shiori up there. You saw her too!
剛才絕對不是看錯了 哲哥不也看到了嗎？
Man, I smell like the sewers now. I gotta take a bath before I go out.
真是的，下水道的臭味都沾到身上了 去都酒吧前還得去洗澡
I'll tell Erika how manly you are, okay?
行了，我會幫你 在繪里香面前說好話的
Oh, you would?
你說真的嗎？
Hold on a sec. How did she get to the other side?
不對，等等，小澪，她怎麼做到的？ 她怎麼到柵欄的另一邊去的？
Yuck.
難吃
No way. Wait!
不是吧，等等
Are we dreaming?
我們是在做夢嗎？
What? You're going? I have expensive shoes on!
甚麼？你要去嗎？小澪 我這可是花了六萬日圓買的皮鞋啊
Hey, that was…
喂，剛才的是…
Mio Kofune and the police officer Tetsu Totsumura.
小舟澪小姐和凸村哲警官
Sis's bad feeling may have been right.
姐姐不好的預感，也許說中了
I wouldn't follow them. It's a trap.
如果是我就不會追上去，肯定是陷阱
At least we know Mio is human. She has immunity.
不過至少可以肯定澪小姐是人類 畢竟她有免疫
Who knows? I guess we'll find out.
出了事我可不管 前面不知道是福是禍
Tokiko.
朱鷺子
I'm surprised you survived this far intruding on forbidden soil, Brother.
闖進禁區居然還能活著啊，哥哥
Answer me! What is this about, Tokiko?
回答我，到底怎麼回事？朱鷺子
She's too far. She's out of range for the nail gun.
太遠了，不在射釘槍的射程內
What are you doing here?
我問你到底在這裡做甚麼
Dumb question.
愚蠢的問題
W-What?
你說甚麼？
Recovering faulty goods. Thank you for bringing Ushioh to me.
我在回收次貨 謝謝你們把潮姐姐帶來
She is tough to find since she's broken.
要找到她真是不容易，因為她壞掉了
She is coming closer. I can reach her in three more steps.
她毫無防備地靠近了 還有三步就到射程內
We'll take care of her from here.
剩下的事情就由我們來處理吧
I won't let you touch Ushioh!
我絕不會讓你碰潮一根汗毛
Please! Stop!
拜託，停下來吧
No, Shinpei.
不對，慎平
Tokiko…
朱鷺子是…
Too bad, Shinpei.
很可惜，慎平哥
I'm human. You can kill shadows, but not humans.
我是人類，你可以殺影子 但殺人，你下不了手吧？
Are you really Tokiko?
你真的是朱鷺子嗎？
Shall we chat for a bit?
要跟我聊聊嗎？
My apologies, Neguro.
不好意思，總是麻煩你，根來護士
How may I help, Doctor?
你找我嗎？醫生
Add this to today's fodder.
今天的食物多加一個
It's almost nine. Hurry and carry it over.
很快就到晚上9點了，趕快搬過去吧
Yes, Doctor. I understand.
好的，醫生，我明白了
We surrender.
我投降
No! Shinpei!
慎平，你怎麼…
Sou!
-窗 -甚麼…
Shinpei's right. It sucks, but we can't win.
慎平是對的，雖然很不甘心 但我們已經沒有勝算了
Don't do anything stupid, Brother.
你可別動甚麼危險的念頭啊，哥哥
Grab her.
抓住她
Ushioh! Dammit! Stop it, Tokiko!
潮，可惡，住手，朱鷺子
Sou. Calm down.
窗，冷靜點
What?
你說甚麼？
She would have already killed her if she wanted to.
如果他們打算殺了潮，潮早就死了
She just wants to take Ushioh. Am I right, Tokiko?
所以他們只是來帶走潮的 我說的沒錯吧，朱鷺子
I haven't figured anything out yet.
我甚麼線索都還沒掌握到
If I can take the silence as a "Yes," then it's still early.
她的沉默可以理解為肯定吧 那就還來得及，還早
Sorry, Ushioh, hang in there. It's just going to be a bit longer.
抱歉了，潮，再忍耐一下 再稍微忍耐一下就好了
Where are you taking her? To your father?
你要帶她去哪裡？去你父親那裡嗎？
You're so clueless, Brother.
你甚麼都不知道，哥哥
I guess it's inevitable. Dad didn't choose you.
不過這也是理所當然的 畢竟爸爸沒有選中你
W-What?
甚麼？
If you've seen this much, there's no point in hiding it anymore.
不過既然你都看到了 我也沒必要再繼續隱瞞下去
This could be a good opportunity to show you everything.
反而是一次過讓你知道一切的好機會
Please put down your weapons. I'll guide you if you comply.
扔掉背包和武器 照我說的做，我就帶你們去
I don't want to take drastic measures. Please come at your own will.
我不想對你們動粗 可以的話，你們自己跟上來吧
Hiruko is waiting.
蛭子大人在等著
You'll miss. A little to the right. Five degrees to the right.
那樣會打偏的 要往右一點，往右五度
Shut up!
囉嗦
Don't worry about me.
不用管我
Fine.
好的
Focus on your own target.
注意力集中在自己的目標上
We lost track of Mio. Is she okay?
我們跟丟了澪小姐，她沒事吧
It's not the time to worry about others. Look around. What is this place?
現在可能不是擔心別人的時候 你看，這裡到底是怎麼回事？
It's like the bottom of the sea.
我們是在海底嗎？
That is a Doflein sea anemone.
這是多弗蘭海葵
Dof… what?
多弗…甚麼？
It lives in the deep sea. I saw it on TV before.
一種深海生物，我以前在電視上看過
They cannot live on land. These must be all shadows.
這種生物不可能在陸地生存 這些應該都是影子
-Behind us! -What?
後面
I don't like this.
真讓人不舒服
You killed that thing twice! Why is it still here?
你不是已經殺掉那傢伙兩次了嗎？ 為甚麼又…
Is it immortal?
不死之身嗎？
Oh? You're not surprised?
奇怪，你不吃驚嗎？
It would make sense if you didn't really die.
假設你沒死的話，一切就都說得通了
You faked being killed, and dove underground. Right?
你裝作被我幹掉的樣子 實際上是潛入了地下，沒錯吧
Sis was suspicious of the sewers.
姐姐認為下水道很可疑
I see. As expected from Hizuru. Why did you return to get in my way?
真不愧是日鶴 為甚麼要回來妨礙我？
I told you I'd kill you if I saw you again.
我說過，下次再見到就會殺了你吧
I guess you wouldn't know, Ryunosuke Minakata.
跟你說你也不明白吧，南方龍之介
-Hey, you. -No!
喂，你…
How do you know that name?
-不對 -那傢伙怎麼會知道你的名字？
I figured out you hid inside Hizuru when we talked in the kid's room.
在小孩房間談話時，我就發現了 沒想到你居然進入日鶴體內
It can't be. Are you Heine?
不可能，是波稻？
It's been 14 years since we saw each other.
所以是14年沒見了嗎？
However, I'm not interested in you. You're only a personality and a memory.
但是我們要找的不是你 不是只有人格和記憶的你
Where is your body?
身體去哪裡了？
Where's the body that stole Mother's right eye?
奪走媽媽右眼的身體呢？
Heine, you're playing make-believe all over again?
波稻，你從一開始 就又在玩扮演遊戲嗎？
This time you're using Shiori Kobayakawa's memory.
這次是用小早川詩織的記憶
It got blocked.
被擋住了
That shot should have hit.
那子彈本應該打中的
I read his memory. Neither Hizuru nor Ryunosuke knows where the body is.
我讀取過記憶了，日鶴和龍之介 都不知道身體去了哪裡
I can't read the old man.
那個老頭的讀取不了
Can I kill him?
要殺了他們嗎？
Sure.
可以
Let's run, Ryunosuke. We can't beat that.
快逃，龍之介，我們打不過的
You've got to be kidding.
開甚麼玩笑？
Don't you get it? We're the ones being hunted!
還不明白嗎？現在被狩獵的是我們
They're not shadows of humans, but of something much more terrible.
那些傢伙不是人類的影子 是更可怕的其他東西
Watch it. He's slightly off.
小心點，那傢伙是偏離的
He's about two seconds ahead.
兩秒左右，往前偏離
Yes. I know.
嗯，我知道
Ryunosuke!
龍之介！
There. One down.
好，搞定一個了
Nezu!
根津先生
Damn you!
去死吧
Oh?
這裡嗎？
Around there?
這個位置嗎？
So close.
真可惜
It's hard to hit two seconds ahead.
這很難啊，要預判又要打中
You're not going after him?
不追嗎？
No need. The blood is dark. I hit the liver.
沒必要了吧，血是黑色的 應該是射穿肝臟了
It's a fatal blow. He'll die soon anyway.
是致命傷，放著不管也很快就會死掉
Where are Ushioh and Shinpei?
潮和慎平他們呢？
They're close, but don't worry. I sent two stray shadows with Tokiko.
已經到那裡了，放心吧 朱鷺子還帶著兩隻野生的
More importantly, I'm really hungry. I can't wait 'til nine o'clock.
別說這些了，我已經餓了 9點還沒到嗎？
Dammit, I have no strength. Shinpei lost his weapon and surrendered.
可惡，身體使不上勁 剛才慎平扔掉武器投降了
He must've decided not to loop before finding out the truth.
因為真相就在眼前 所以還不想輪迴嗎？
He's going to go as far as he can. Right, Shinpei?
你打算追查到極限為止，對吧？慎平
That wasn't me!
不是我
It's Hiruko. She's hungry.
是蛭子大人，她餓了
I have accepted what I do.
我接受我自己所做的事
I won't ask for forgiveness. I just want you all to understand it.
我不會尋求你們原諒，但事已至此 我只希望大家都能接受
Dad is opposed to telling you though, Brother.
雖然父親反對我告訴哥哥
I won't warn you not to tell anyone, because you can't.
但不需要誰來警告我 我也知道不能說出去
But please don't tell Mio, Shinpei.
不過慎平哥，請你千萬不要告訴澪
I don't want Mio to find out what you see and learn here.
接下來看到的、知道的 都不要告訴她
I won't get Mio involved with this.
我不打算把澪牽扯進來
Good. You're kind.
那就好，你真是個好人
A long shadow stretches to the ceiling.
長長的影子一直延伸到洞頂
At the foot of that shadow…
那影子的底部…
Nine o'clock sharp.
剛好9點
Time to eat.
進食時間到了